<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Coding, Cricket, Trading, Random thoughts</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 11:09:42 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 11:09:42 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Second test - West Indies v India</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow. what an exciting test that was! And well done to the West Indies for making the series interesting. I needed a break after that. Here is my analysis of how I traded the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparation. Recently I read an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bruce_Kovner&quot;&gt;Bruce Kovner&lt;/a&gt; who said something that has stuck with me: &lt;em&gt;“One of the jobs of a good trader is to imagine alternative scenarios. I try to form many different mental pictures of what the world should be like and wait for one of them to be confirmed. You keep trying them on one at a time. Inevitably, most of these pictures will turn out to be wrong - that is, only a few elements of the picture may prove correct. But then, all of a sudden, you will find that in one picture, nine out of ten elements click. That scenario then becomes your image of the world reality”&lt;/em&gt;. I now spend about 1 hour or so before the start of every day thinking of various scenarios and reasons for them to occur. As the play unfolds, I see a scenario crystallize and trade accordingly. For e.g. on Day 5 of the test, in one of my scenarios, I conjured up reasons for West Indies to save the test match (pitch slowing up, bowlers not looking in rhythm etc) and after an hour of play, it looked like West Indies had a good chance of saving the match. So I layed India when possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risk Management. Most of my trades were 100-200 GBP stakes. And the maximum liability I had at one point was 250 GBP. On a few occasions I wanted to increase my stakes but I resisted temptation and consequently I was able to think with a clear head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trading the rain. I want to learn how to trade the rain better. A significant portion of my winnings was due to trading the rain but I think I can improve. I will also lean more on my lovely wife to help me with this; she has a Masters in Meteorolgy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No data-driven approach. I am currently trading on instinct. With 2020s I have defined very clear edges based on my database and I execute my trades using these edges. For test matches however, I have not defined any such edges. And I dont think this is most efficient way of trading. In the upcoming days, I will think of some approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I am very happy with my trading during the match. I prepared well and executed my trades without any stress. And to be honest, I think I got a little bit lucky too. Almost every trade I made went in my favour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshot2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Profit screenshot&quot; style=&quot;width: 800px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Third test&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to build on my trading from the second test. Given the amount of rain present over the next 5 days and the relatively flat pitch I will look to back the draw when possible. I also think West Indies would have gained a bit of confidence from the previous test and will look to build on that. However, I will wait and watch before making my moves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been coding a couple of things on the side - a bot, and a more data-driven approach to trading 2020s. I will write about them later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and have a good week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/07/29/second-test-westindies-india/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/07/29/second-test-westindies-india/</guid>
        
        
        <category>test</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First test match</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I traded my first full test match: India v West Indies. I usually enjoy watching test matches but at times I struggled to sit through this one. India dominated from start to finish and the market was relatively stagnant. After 4 days, I lost a bit of money but overall I learnt quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I traded this test?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of every day, I did my research and thought about the various ways the match could unfold. For the first 2 days I traded relatively well but things went downhill from there. Mid-way through the first session on Day 3, I backed the draw. The draw price was crashing and I was hoping to cash out with a nice profit during the lunch break, except… Bravo decided to get out at the stroke of lunch. Just after lunch, Shami picked up two wickets in one over and I was a dead duck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am disappointed in myself for the way I traded the remainder of the test match. I backed the draw at high prices and kept waiting for a fightback in anticipation of green-ing out. This was quite dangerous given that all five of the Indian bowlers were bowling very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the benefit of hindsight, I probably lost money due to the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A bit of bad luck with the wicket of Bravo on Day 3. However, if presented the same situation I will trade the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A lot of bad trading on Days 3 and 4. Given that the Indian bowlers bowled well, I should have been more wary of backing the draw. If I had back the draw, I should have dipped in and out of the markets looking for small profits rather than large ones.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Over-estimating the West Indies. I know this is a poor West Indies team but I expected a bit of fightback at some stage, and this didnt eventuate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second test&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really looking forward to the 2nd test starting today and I hope to implement some of the lessons learnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pitch is green and the last 15 matches at Jamaica have not seen a draw. So I am going to back the bowling team tomorrow and lay the draw when possible. I think a green pitch might favour the West Indies slightly in that it will bring their bowlers more into play (Brathwaite and Holder looked especially toothless in the first test). And I hope we see a bit of Alzarri Joseph!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I dont intend to turn this into a profit/loss blog, I might attach screenshots from time to time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marquestrading.github.io/images/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Loss screenshot&quot; style=&quot;width: 800px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/07/29/first-test-match/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/07/29/first-test-match/</guid>
        
        
        <category>test</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Caribbean Premier League</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My first step towards becoming a consistent trader involved defining my edges. Most readers of this blog already know what an ‘edge’ is but for the non-traders: an edge is just a condition which indicates a higher probability of something occuring. When I see the condition I place my bet. Here are the results of my 4 defined edges so far which I have been testing during the T20 blast and CPL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Num of matches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Returns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Edge 1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;256%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Edge 2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;-93%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Edge 3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;-86%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Edge 4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;-71%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to be clear: £10 trades on Edge 2 would have resulted in a loss of £9.3 after 10 matches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will test each edge for 20 matches before deciding whether it is profitable. The good news is that Edge 1 seems promising. It is quite rudimentary at this stage and I have a few ideas on how to improve it. I am currently trading with only £2 bets but I will soon start increasing my bet amounts. The advantage of defining my edges and trading rigidly with them is that I am no longer stressed. I am able to take a loss just as easily as a win. You might argue that I have no right to be stressed when Im only staking £2! But you get the idea. Edges 2, 3 and 4 are not doing well yet but there is still a long way to go before I judge them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another note, the CPL has taken a slight toll on me. I stay up trading late into the night, find it hard to sleep and then I dream about cricket in my sleep. While I enjoy cricket I certainly dont want to dream about it. So from next week, I will switch my focus to the West Indies v India test matches which are during far more reasonable hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 10:06:25 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/07/14/caribbean-premier-league/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/07/14/caribbean-premier-league/</guid>
        
        
        <category>CPL</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome - My journey to become a Consistent Trader</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading my first post. Just to introduce myself: In 2006 I graduated from University with a degree in Computer Science and found a job at a large corporation. Pretty soon I realised that this was not my scene. Whilst I enjoyed some parts of the job, I really despised the corporate culture - climbing the ladder, dealing with office politics etc. I could go on and on. So I started thinking about my future and came to the realisation that I wanted to work for myself or start a technology company. The problem - I had no decent or even semi-decent ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile, I would really enjoy watching sports and having an odd bet from time to time. In January 2015, I stumbled upon Betfair cricket markets and was stunned by the amount of money exchanged over a game of cricket. After doing some research I found that there were quite a few ‘Cricket Traders’ who made a comfortable living doing this. I really love cricket and betting - I wanted a piece of the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I convinced myself that this would be quite easy. After all, I had grown up playing cricket and I watched a lot of it on TV. But how &lt;strong&gt;wrong&lt;/strong&gt; was I? In the following 12 months, I found that if I backed the batting team a wicket would fall, if I sensed a wicket I was too scared to back the bowling team; I would chase losing positions so as to avoid ending the day with a loss. The market was contrived to take my money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I read ‘Trading in the Zone’ by Mark Douglas. The book resonated with me so much that I read it twice, then a third time and I took notes. I have tried to internalize Mark’s concepts and focus on his principles of having a probabilistic mind-set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2016, I quit my job to trade sports full time. I have given myself three years to crack this. This blog will document my journey from a novice trader to hopefully a consistent one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 10:06:25 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/06/28/welcome/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/06/28/welcome/</guid>
        
        
        <category>introduction</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
