<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Coding, Cricket, Trading, Random thoughts</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 06:51:49 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 06:51:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome - My journey to become a Consistent Trader</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading my first post. Just to introduce myself: In 2006 I graduated from University with a degree in Computer Science and found a job at a large corporation. Pretty soon I realised that this was not my scene. Whilst I enjoyed some parts of the job, I really despised the corporate culture - climbing the ladder, dealing with office politics etc. I could go on and on. So I started thinking about my future and came to the realisation that I wanted to work for myself or start a technology company. The problem - I had no decent or even semi-decent ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile, I would really enjoy watching sports and having an odd bet from time to time. In January 2015, I stumbled upon Betfair cricket markets and was stunned by the amount of money exchanged over a game of cricket. After doing some research I found that there were quite a few ‘Cricket Traders’ who made a comfortable living doing this. I really love cricket and betting - I wanted a piece of the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I convinced myself that this would be quite easy. After all, I had grown up playing cricket and I watched a lot of it on TV. But how &lt;strong&gt;wrong&lt;/strong&gt; was I? In the following 12 months, I found that if I backed the batting team a wicket would fall, if I sensed a wicket I was too scared to back the bowling team; I would chase losing positions so as to avoid ending the day with a loss. The market was contrived to take my money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I read ‘Trading in the Zone’ by Mark Douglas. The book resonated with me so much that I read it twice, then a third time and I took notes. I have tried to internalize Mark’s concepts and focus on his principles of having a probabilistic mind-set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2016, I quit my job to trade sports full time. I have given myself three years to crack this. This blog will document my journey from a novice trader to hopefully a consistent one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 10:06:25 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/06/28/welcome/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/06/28/welcome/</guid>
        
        
        <category>introduction</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
